这里是博克岛
This is Berk
有像北极那样12天绝望的严寒 也有南极酷冷的垂死之感
It's 12 days North of hopeless and a few degrees South of freezing to death.
岛就坐落在"悲剧子午线"上
It's located solidly on the Meridian of Misery.
这就是我的家乡 简而言之: 一成不变
My village. In a word: sturdy.
现在这里是第七代人了 但是房子都还很新
It's been here for seven generations but every single building is new.
我们打渔 打猎 还可以欣赏迷人的夕阳
We have fishing, hunting, and a charming view of the sunsets.
唯一的问题是害虫
The only problems are the pests.
一般来说 害虫都是老鼠或是蚊子
You see, most places have mice or mosquitoes.
但我们的是
We have...
龙
Dragons.
大多数人选择离开 但是不是我们
Most people would leave, but not us.
我们是维京人
We're Vikings.
我们拥有顽强
We stubbornness issues.
我叫Hiccup
My name is Hiccup.
我知道不是什么伟大的名字 但是也不是最糟的
Great name, I know. But it's not the worst.
父母们相信一个难听的名字可以驱赶地精和恶魔
Parents believe a hideous name will frighten off Gnomes and Trolls.
好像我们维京勇士的壮举还不如一个名字
Like our charming Viking demeanor wouldn't do that.
早
'Morning.
你在这里做什么? 进去!
What are you doing here? Get inside!
快回去!
Get back inside!
Hiccup! 你又出来干什么  你出来干什么? 回去!
Hiccup! What is he doing out again... What are you doing out? Get inside!
这是大块头Stoick 部落的首领
That's Stoick the Vast, Chief of the tribe.
他们说他还是婴儿的时候 他就能把龙头从它的脖子上扭下来
They say that when he was a baby he popped a Dragon's head clean off its shoulders.
我相信吗? 当然信
Do I believe it? Yes, I do.
有哪些龙?
What have we got?
Gronckles Nadders Zipplebacks  哦 还有凶魇群龙
Gronckles, Nadders, Zipplebacks... Oh, and hordes of Monstruous Nightmares.
有没有夜煞?
Any Night Furys?
现在还没有   很好
None so far.   Good.
点燃火炬!
Light the torches!
哦 很高兴你也来参加这样的晚会 我还以为你被抓走了
Oh, nice of you to join the party. I thought you'd been carried off.
谁? 我? 得了吧  我肌肉太多 它们不喜欢
Who? Me? Nah, come on... I'm way too muscular for their taste.
它们不知道怎么吃所有的  这些
They wouldn't know what to do with all... this.
好吧 它们需要牙签 是吧?
Well, they need toothpicks, don't they?
那个脾气暴躁 还装着义肢的傻瓜叫Gobber
The meathead with the attitude and interchangeable hands, is Gobber.
我从小做他的学徒
I have been his apprentice ever since I was little.
嗯 比现在小一点
Well, littler
我们去空旷的地方防守 用投射器反攻
We move to the moor defenses. We'll counterattack with the catapults.
看见了吗? 老村落 却有很多很多新房子
See? Old village. Lots and lots of new houses.
着火了!
Fire!
哦 那是Fishlegs
Oh, and that's Fishlegs
那是Snotlout
Snotlout
双胞胎Ruffnut和Tuffnut
The twins, Ruffnut and Tuffnut...
还有
And...
是Astrid
Astrid.
喔 他们的工作酷多了
Aww, their job is so much cooler.
哦 拜托 放我出去 我要建功!
Oh, come on. Let me out, please. I need to make my mark!
哦 你已经做了很多的贡献了 但是都是错误的
Oh, you have made plenty of marks. All in the wrong places.
就两分钟 我会杀了一条龙的 我的人生就将从此改变
Please, 2 minutes. I'll kill a dragon. My life will get infinitely better.
我甚至能去约会
I might even get a date.
你连榔头都举不起 连斧头都挥不动
You can't lift a hammer. You can't swing an axe.
甚至这其中一个都扔不出
You can't even throw one of these.
好 好 但是这个可以帮我扔
Okay, fine, but this will throw it for me.
看见了吗 就和我说的一样
See, now this right here is what I'm talking about.
但是 它  它只要再稍稍校准下
But it... it's a mild calibration issue.
Hiccup 如果你想去和龙战斗
Hiccup, if you ever want to get out there to fight dragons
你必须改变这些
you need to stop all....
这些
this.
但是你指的是我的全身
But you just pointed to all of me.
是 就是全身
Yes, that's it.
要脱胎换骨
Stop being all of you.
哦    哦 是
Oh...   Oh, yes.
先生 您这是在玩一个危险的游戏
You sir, are playing a dangerous game...
保持维京人这种原始的特质
keeping this much raw Vikingness contained.
后果会很严重!   我会承担的
There will be consequences!   I take my chances.
去磨剑 快走!
Sword, sharpened, now!
总有一天 我会到那里的
One day I'll get out there.
因为在这里 杀死龙意味着一切
Because killing a dragon is everything around here.
打倒一条Nadder至少可以让我得到注意
A Nadderhead is sure to get me at least noticed.
Gronckles很强硬
Gronckles are tough.
打倒一条肯定可以找到一个女朋友
Taking down one of those would definitely get me a girlfriend.
一条Zippleback:
A Zippleback: ...
不太现实 两个头 双倍的难度
exotic, two heads, twice the status.
他们找到羊了!
They found the sheep!
向下面集中火力!
Concentrate fire over the lower bank!
快!
Hurry up!
开火!
Fire!
还有 凶魇
And then, there's the Monstruous Nightmare.
只有最棒的维京人敢挑战它们
Only the best Vikings go after those.
它们有一个讨人厌的坏习惯 把自己点燃
They have this nasty habit of setting themselves on fire.
再次填装!
Reload!
我可以应付
I'll take care of this.
但是最让人觊觎的龙 还没有人见到过
But the ultimate prize is the dragon no one's ever seen.
我们叫它
We call it the...
夜煞!   趴下!
Night Fury!   Get down!
跳!
Jump!
它从不偷东西 从不现身 然而
This thing never steals food, never shows itself, and...
从未失手
never misses.
没人杀死过夜煞
No one has ever killed a Night Fury.
这就是我想成为第一个的原因
That's why I'm going to be the first.
守住阵地 Hiccup 他们需要我
Mind the fort, Hiccup. They need me out there.
呆着! 别动!
Stay! Put!
就这里
There.
你知道我是什么意思
You know what I mean.
Hiccup 你在干什么?   回来!
Hiccup, what are you doing?   Come back here!
我知道 马上回来!
Yeah, I know, Be right back!
自己小心!
Mind yourself!
那些恶魔还有些能量
The devils still have some juice in them.
来吧
Come on.
给我些目标 给我目标
Give me something to shoot at. Give me something to shoot at.
哦! 我击中了? 是的 我击中了!
Oh! I hit it? Yes, I hit it!
有人看见吗?
Did anybody see that?
除了你
Except for you.
别让它们跑了!   好的!
Do not let them escape!   Right!
你等死吧
You're all out.
哦 还有一件事你要知道
Oh, and there's one more thing you need to know...
抱歉 爸爸
Sorry, Dad.
但是我击中了夜煞
Okay, but I hit a Night Fury.
和上几次不一样 爸爸!
It's not like the last few times, Dad!
我是说 我真的击中了
I mean, I really actually hit...
你们正在忙 我很漂亮地击中了
You guys were busy and I had a very clear shot.
它掉在黑区 快派人过去搜
It went down just off Raven Point. Let's get a search party out there before...
闭嘴!
Stop!
给我闭嘴!
Just, stop!
你一出门 灾难就降临
Every time you step outside disaster falls.
你没发现我还有更大的麻烦吗?
Can you not see that I have bigger problems?
冬天临近了 我还得喂饱全村人!
Winter is almost here and I have an entire village to feed!
看这身材差距 如果都不像你们这么硕大 村子也可以少负担些口粮?
Between you and me, the village could do with a little less feeding, don't you think?
这不是在开玩笑 Hiccup!
This isn't a joke, Hiccup!
你就不能老实一点?
Why can't you follow the simplest orders?
我控制不住自己 每当我看到龙 就想
I, I can't stop myself. I see a dragon and I have to just...
杀了它 爸爸 这就是我
kill it. You know, it's who I am, Dad.
哦 你可以胜任很多职责 但决不是捕龙者 Hiccup
Oh, you are many things, Hiccup, but a dragon killer is not one of them.
回到屋子里去 确保他回去
Get back to the house. Make sure he gets there.
我还得收拾他的烂摊子
I have his mess to clean up.
演出结束了
Quite the performance.
好厉害的败家子啊 太帅了!
I've never seen any one mess up that badly. That helped!
谢谢 谢谢 我一直在努力
Thank you. Thank you. I was trying.
我真的射中了一条   当然 Hiccup
I really did hit one.   Sure, Hiccup.
他从来不听我说的   哎 每个家庭基本都这样
He never listens.   Well, it runs in the family.
就算信了 也满腹牢骚
And when he does, it's always with this disappointed scowl
就好像有人偷吃了他三明治中的肉
like someone skimped on the meat in his sandwich.
不好意思 女招待 我想你搞错了吧
Excuse me, barmaid. I'm afraid you brought me the wrong offspring.
我要的是壮如牛的男孩 另外还得有勇气和荣誉感
I ordered an extra large boy with beefy arms. Extra guts and glory on the side.
这个 你给我的分明是火柴棒!
This here. This is a talking fish bone!
不 你想错了
Now, you're thinking about this all wrong.
他在乎的不是你的外表 他看重的是你的灵魂
It's not so much what you look like. It's what's inside that he can't stand.
谢谢你的总结
Thank you for summing that up.
关键是别强迫自己做力所不能及的事
Look, the point is, stop trying so hard to be something you're not.
我只是想和你们大伙一样
I just want to be one of you guys.
要么我们赶走那群龙 要么它们消灭我们
Either we face them or they'll finish us.
想要把龙赶走只有一招
It's the only way we'll be rid of them.
如果我们找到并摧毁龙巢 它们就会离开
If we find the nest and destroy it, the dragons will leave.
它们会去别处定居
They'll find another home.
在水面冻结前 我们再搜寻一次
One more search, before the ice sets in.
以前派出的船都失踪了
Those ships never come back.
我们是维京人 冒险是维京人的天职
We're Vikings. It's an occupational hazard.
那么 谁和我一起去?
Now who's with me?
好吧  留下来的人照看Hiccup
Alright... Those who stay will look after Hiccup.
我去收拾行李了
I'll pack my undies.
不 我需要你留下来训练新手
No, I need you to stay, and train some new recruits.
哦 太棒了 是的 我忙时 Hiccup可以来帮忙
Oh, perfect, yeah. And while I'm busy Hiccup can cover the store.
他负责熔铁 磨刀 有很多时间
Molten steel, razor sharp blades, lots of time to himself...
会有什么问题呢?
What could possibly go wrong?
我该怎么办呢 Gobber?
Oh, what am I going to do with him, Gobber?
让他和其他人一起训练
Put him in training with the others.
我是认真的   我也是
No, I'm serious.   So am I.
在你放出第一条龙之前 他就会被吓死
He'd be killed before you let the first dragon out of its cage.
你不了解   我了解
Oh, you don't know that.   I do know that.
不 你不了解   我了解
No， you don't   No, actually, I do.
不 你不了解   听我说 你知道他是怎样的一个人
No, you don't.   Listen, you know what he's like.
从他会爬开始 我就发现他  和别人不一样
From the time he could crawl he's been... different.
他从来不听我的话 他宁可盯着看麻雀
He doesn't listen. He has the attention span of a sparrow.
我带他去捕鱼 他却跑去找  巨魔!
I take him fishing and he goes hunting for... for Trolls!
真有巨魔! 它们偷了你的袜子
Trolls exist! They steal your socks.
但它们只偷左脚的 为什么呢?
But only the left ones. What's with that?
我小的时候    哦 又来了
When I was a boy...   Oh, here we go.
我父亲让我用头去撞石头 我照做了
My father told me to bang my head against a rock, and I did it.
我觉得这很疯狂 但是我没问他为什么
I thought it was crazy, but I didn't question him.
你猜怎么着了?
And you know what happened?
你犯头疼病了   石头裂成了两半
You got a headache.   That rock split in two.
这让我体会到一个维京人的潜力 Gobber
It taught me what a Viking could do, Gobber.
他能撞碎山脉 夷平森林
He could crush mountains, level forests,
征服大海
tame seas!
在我还是个孩子的时候 我就知道我会变成什么
Even as a boy I knew what I was, what I had to become...
可是Hiccup却不能
Hiccup is not that boy.
你不能阻止他 Stoick 你只应该为他做好准备
You can't stop him, Stoick. You can only prepare him.
我知道这希望渺茫 但是你不能总是保护他
I know it seems hopeless, but the truth is you won't always be around to protect him.
他迟早会再出去 说不定就是现在
He's going to get out there again. He's probably out there now.
哦 上帝不喜欢我
Oh, the Gods hate me.
有些人会弄丢刀子 杯子
Some people lose their knife or their mug.
不 不应该是我啊! 我弄丢了一条龙
No, not me! I managed to lose an entire dragon.
嗷!
Ow!
哦 哇? 这是我  我干的吗? 哦 是我干的!
Oh, wow? I... I did it? Oh, I did it!
这玩意儿真是万能的 是的!
This fixes everything. Yes!
我放倒了一头大野兽!
I have brought down this mighty beast!
我要杀了你 可怜的龙
I'm gonna kill you, dragon.
我会  我会切出你的心脏 交给我爸
I'm gonna... I'm gonna cut out your heart and take it to my father.
我是维京人
I'm a Viking.
我是维京人!
I'm a Viking!
是我做的
I did this.
Hiccup啊
Hiccup.
爸爸? 呃
Dad? Uh...
我有话和你说 爸爸   儿子 我也正想和你说些事
I have to talk to you, Dad.   I need to speak with you too, son.
我认为你该学习屠龙了   我不想屠龙
I think it's time you to learned to fight dragons.   I don't want to fight dragons.
什么?   什么?
What?   What?
你先说   还是你先说吧
Uh, you go first.   No, no, you go first.
好吧 你如愿以偿了
All right. You got your wish.
屠龙训练 明早开始
Dragon training. You start in the morning.
哦 早知道我就先说了
Oh man, I should have gone first.
呃 我一直在想 你也知道 我们屠龙的人手过剩 但是
Uh, cause I was thinking. You know, we have a surplus of dragon fighting Vikings but...
后勤的人手不够
do we have enough breadmaking Vikings, or small home repair Vikings...
你需要这个   我不想屠龙
You'll need this.   I don't want to fight dragons.
哦 来吧 你能行的   换句话说 爸爸 我杀不了龙
Oh come on, yes you do.   Rephrase. Dad, I can't kill dragons.
但是你会杀死龙的
But you will kill dragons.
不 我很确定 我不会
No, I'm really very extra sure that I won't.
是时候了 Hiccup   你没听我说吗?
It's time, Hiccup.   Can you not hear me?
这事很严肃 儿子
This is serious, son.
当你握紧这把战斧 你就肩负起了我们整个维京族
When you carry this axe, you carry all of us with you.
也就是说: 你能像我们一样走路 像我们一样讲话 像我们一样思考
Which means: You walk like us. You talk like us. You think like us.
不再如此  懦弱   你只是在对我指手画脚
No more of... this.   You just gestured to all of me.
就这么定了?   一直是你在自言自语
Deal?   This conversation is feeling very onesided.
就这么定了?
Deal?
定了
Deal.
棒极了
Good.
好好训练
Train hard.
我会回来的 大概吧
I'll be back. Probably.
我也会在这里等你 也许
And I'll be here, maybe.
欢迎参加训龙课程
Welcome to dragon training.
没有回头路
No turning back.
我真希望我能被烧伤
I hope I get some serious burns.
我只希望肩膀或者后背有一些抓伤
I'm hoping for some mauling, like on my shoulder or lower back.
是啊 伤疤什么的 很有意思
Yeah, it's only fun if you get a scar out of it.
是啊 这不是闹着玩的 对吗? 我喜欢疼痛
Yeah, no kidding, right? Pain, love it.
哦 天哪 谁让他进来的?
Oh, great, who let him in?
开始吧 最棒的那个人
Lets get started. The recruit who does best,
能得到在全村人面前杀死第一条龙的荣耀!
will win the honor of killing his first dragon in front of the entire village.
Hiccup都已经杀了一条夜煞了 这点小事对他不过是自降身份罢了吧 ?
Hiccup already killed a Night Fury, so does that disqualify him or...?
我能转到其他的训练班里吗?
Can I transfer to the class with the cool Vikings?
别担心 你又弱又小 被龙当成目标的概率也低
Don't worry. You're small and you're weak, That will make you a less of a target.
和你这样的豆芽菜比起来 它们更喜欢一些强壮的维京少年
They'll see you as sick or insane and go after the more Vikinglike teens instead.
在这扇门后面的只是你们以后会遇到的所有龙里
Behind these doors are just a few of the
微不足道的几种
many species you will learn to fight.
致命Nadder  C速度8 防御16
The Deadly Nadder.   Speed: 8, Armor: 16.
丑陋Zippleback   潜行11速翻倍
The Hideous Zippleback.   11 Stealth times two.
凶魇  C火力15
The Monstrous Nightmare.   Fire Power: 15.
恶龙Terror   8攻12毒
The Terrible Terror.   Attack: 8, Venom: 12.
给我住嘴!
Can you stop that!
还有Gronckle   咬合力8
And the Gronckle.   Jaw Strength: 8.
喂 等一下 你不是应该先教我们吗?
Woah, woah, wait, aren't you going to teach us first?
我一直坚信实践是最好的学习方法
I believe in learning on the job.
今天是龙穴生存日 如果你被火球喷个正着 就会当场毙命
Today is about survival. If you get blasted, you're dead.
快! 你们最需要的是什么?
Quick! What's the first thing you're going to need?
医生?   加速魔药?
A doctor?   + 5 Speed?
盾?   盾牌! 盾牌在那
A shield?   Shield. Go.
你们最重要的装备就是盾牌
Your most important piece of equipment is your shield.
如果只能在剑和盾牌里选一样
If you must make a choice between a sword or a shield.
盾牌会是你唯一的选择
Take the shield.
把你的脏手从我的盾牌上拿开!   那里不是还有一堆吗?
Get your hands off my shield.   There's like a million shields.
拿那一个 这个上面画的是一朵花 女孩子喜欢
Take that one. It has a flower on it. Girls like flowers.
哦哦 现在倒是又有了点血迹了
Oops, now this one has blood on it.
Tuffnut Ruffnut 出局
Tuffnut, Ruffnut, your out.
什么?   什么?
What?   What?
这个盾牌别有用处 噪音
Those shields are good for another thing. Noise.
用武器敲打盾牌发出噪音 让龙无法识别目标
Make lots of it and throw off a dragon's aim.
所有的龙能发出的火球都是有限的
All dragons have a limited number of shots.
一条Gronckle有几个?
How many does a Gronckle have?
5?   不 是6发
Five?   No, six.
没错 六发 你们每个人都刚好分到那么一下
Right, six. Thats one for each of you.
Fishlegs 出局
Fishlegs, out.
Hiccup 躲回去!
Hiccup, get in there!
对了 我把我家的地下室改装成训练室了
So anyway, I moved into my parent's basement?
你应该什么时候过来玩玩 你一直都有在锻炼的对不对?
You should come by sometimes to work out, You look like you work out.
Snotlout 出局
Snotlout, your done.
我想只剩下你和我了?   不 你还是孤军奋战吧
So I guess it's just you and me.   Nope, just you.
还剩下一发
One shot left.
Hiccup啊!
Hiccup!
那么六发都完了 你这个大香肠 滚回窝里去睡觉吧
And that's 6. Go back to bed you overgrown sausage.
你还会有其他机会的 别担心
You'll get another chance. Don't you worry.
记住 一条龙
Remember, a dragon will always...
只会为杀戮而行动
always go for the kill.
那你为什么没有这么做呢?
So why didn't you?
哦 这真是太蠢了
Well this was stupid.
你为什么不飞走呢?
Why don't you just fly away?
好吧 今天Astrid在训练场有什么地方做错了?
Alright, where did Astrid go wrong in the ring today?
我选错了翻跟头的时机 没有做好 还摔倒了
I mistimed my sommersault dive. It was sloppy. It threw off my reverse tumble.
是 我们都看到了   不 不 你太优秀了 一直这么出类拔萃
Yeah, we noticed.   No, no you were great. That was so Astrid.
她是对的 你们都应该对自己更加严格 那Hiccup又哪里做错了?
She's right. You have to be tough on yourselves. Where did Hiccup go wrong?
呃 他就不应该出现   他该让自己被吃掉
Uh, he showed up?   He didn't get eaten.
他从来不呆在该呆的地方
He's never where he should be.
谢谢 Astrid 你们需要把这东西背得滚瓜烂熟
Thank you, Astrid. You need to live and breathe this stuff.
飞龙图鉴  这上面记载了我们对所有龙的一切知识
The Dragon Manual... Everything we know about every dragon we know of.
今天晚上不会有偷袭了 别磨蹭
No attacks tonight. Hurry up.
什么? 你是说我们要读书?   我们明明还活着却要读书?
Wait? You mean read?   While we're still alive?
我们明明可以直接把龙杀掉 为什么还要读这鬼东西?
Why read words when you can just kill the stuff the words tell you stuff about?
哦 这本书我读了7遍了
Oh, I've read it like 7 times.
有一种水龙会把沸水喷你一脸
There's this water dragon that sprays boiling water at your face
还有这一种 有时候会把自己埋起来一个星期
and there's this other one that buries itself for like a week...
是啊 听起来不错 曾经我有机会读这个书
Yeah, sounds great. There was a chance I was going to read that.
但是现在
But now...
你们读吧 屠龙的工作交给我就行了
You guys read, I'll go kill something.
喂!
Hey!
看来我们要合用一本书了?   你看吧
So I guess we'll share?   Read it.
嗯 看来只剩下我一个人了? 好吧 嗯 呃  明天见
All mine then? Wow. So, okay. I'll see you uh... tomorrow.
龙族评级
Dragon Classifications
冲击级 恐怖级 传说级
Strike Class, Fear Class, Mystery Class.
雷鼓 这种神出鬼没的孤傲的龙藏逸在深海的洞窟或者黑暗的潮池里
Thunder Drum. This reclusive dragon inhabits sea caves and dark tide pools.
一旦被惊动 它们就会发出惊天地泣鬼神的咆哮 方圆数尺之内 全无活口
When startled, the Thunder Drum produces a concussive sound that can kill a man at close range.
危险度高 见者毙命
Extremely dangerous. Kill on sight.
Timberjack: 这种巨型生物的尖锐翅膀能将参天大树拦腰砍断
Timberjack: This gigantic creature has razorsharp wings that can slice through fullgrown trees.
危险度高 见者毙命
Extremely dangerous. Kill on sight.
Skulldren: 向敌人乱喷沸水 极度危险
Skulldren: Sprays scalding water on its victim. Extremely dangerous...
Changeling: 哪怕只是刚出生的幼龙也能喷射致命毒液 见者毙命
Changeling: Even newly hatch dragons can spray acid. Kill on sight.
Gronckle Zippleback 还有Skrill
Gronckle, Zippleback, The Skrill,
以及Boneknapper和Whispering Death
Boneknapper, Whispering Death.
烧死 活埋 生吞
Burns its victims. Buries its victims. Chokes its victims.
把内脏全都挖出来
Turns victims inside out.
危险度超高  危险度超高
Extremely dangerous... Extremely dangerous...
见者毙命  见者毙命  见者毙命
Kill on sight... Kill on sight... Kill on sight...
夜煞: 速度未知 大小未知
Night Fury: Speed unknown. Size unknown.
闪电与死神的不洁之子
The unholy offspring of lightning and death itself.
不要尝试去战斗
Never engage this dragon.
唯一的选择: 躲藏起来 祈祷别被找到
Your only chance: Hide and pray it does not find you.
很近了 我几乎能闻到它们了
I can almost smell them. They're close.
慢慢来
Steady.
让我们进去吧   左满舵
Take us in.   Hard to port.
地狱犬之门啊
The Hell Hounds gate.
左满舵
Hard to port.
嘿 我刚注意到 书上没有什么关于夜煞的资料
Hey, you know, I just happened to notice, the book had nothing on Night Furys.
还有另外的书呢? 或是续集? 也许是仅仅提到?
Is there like another book? or a sequel? Maybe a little Night Fury pamphlet?
注意 Hiccup! 你在搞什么
Focus Hiccup! You're not even trying.
今天学的是攻击!
Today is all about attack!
Nadder又轻又快 你必须更轻更快
Nadder's are quick and light on their feet. You be quicker and lighter.
我开始怀疑这种教学方法了
I'm really beginning to question your teaching methods.
找龙的弱点 每条龙都有
Look for its blind spot. Every dragon has one.
找到了 躲好 然后攻击
Find it. Hide in it, and strike.
你洗澡了吗?   你不喜欢它 那就快找到盲点躲起来
Do you ever bathe?   You don't like it, then just get your own blind spot.
我给你找一个怎么样?
How about I give you one?
盲点 不错 致命弱点 还得努力
Blind spot, yes. Death spot, notsomuch.
嘿 嘿 那么怎么才能接近夜煞呢?
Hey, hey, so how would one sneak up on a Night Fury?
甚至没有人见到过 活下来做好记录 现在 快进去!
No one's ever met one, and lived to tell the tale. Now, get in there!
我知道 我的意思是假设
I know, I know but hypothetically...
小心 宝贝 我能处理
Watch out, babe, I'll take care of this.
阳光太刺眼了 Astrid
The sun was in my eyes, Astrid.
你想让我做什么? 挡住阳光?
What do you want me to do? Block out the sun?
我可以 但是现在没时间
I can do that. I don't have time right now.
有人看到过瞌睡龙吗?   Hiccup!
Has anyone ever seen one napping?   Hiccup!
Hiccup啊!
Hiccup!
在战场还能谈恋爱   她能做得更好
Love on the battlefield.   She could do better.
让  让  我为什么不让我
L... Let me... why don't you...
喔! 喔! 喔!
Ow! Ow! Ow!
干得好 Astrid
Well done, Astrid.
这对你来说又是笑话吗?
Is this some kind of a joke to you?
我们马上要接过父母的武器 搞清楚你是哪一边的
Our parent's war is about to become ours. Figure out which side your on.
呃? 你没有牙
Huh? Toothless.
我能肯定你有
I could of sworn you have...
牙
teeth.
呃 不  不  不
Uh, uh... no, no... no...
我  我没有更多的了
I... I don't have anymore.
它一扭 咬下了我的一只手 吞了下去
And with one twist, he took my hand and swallowed it whole.
我看到它脸上的表情 一定在说美味极了
And I saw the look in his face. I was delicious.
它一定回去大肆宣传了 因为不到一个月
He must have passed the word, because it wasn't a month
另一条咬下了我的一条腿
before another one of them took my leg.
你的手在龙的肚子里不会感到奇怪吗?
Isn't it weird to think that your hand was inside a dragon?
就好比如果你还能控制你的手 你就可以由内攻外
Like, if your mind was still in control of it, you could have killed the dragon from the inside
通过捏爆它的心脏而取胜
by crushing his heart or something.
我此刻真的非常生气 我发誓
I swear, I'm so angry right now.
要为你那优雅的手和美丽的腿复仇
I'll avenge your beautiful hand and your beautiful foot.
我要亲眼目睹自己砍下打的每一条龙的  腿!
I'll chop of the legs of every dragon I fight... with my face!
不 要砍下龙的翅膀和尾巴
No. It's the wings and the tails you really want.
如果它飞不了了 它也活不久了
If it can't fly, it can't get away.
一条不能飞的龙就是临死的龙
A downed dragon is a dead dragon.
是   是
Yeah.   Yeah.
好了 我要去睡觉了
Alright, I'm off to bed.
你们也早点休息啊 明天还有大玩意儿
You should be too. Tomorrow we get to the big boys.
我们慢慢地逼近凶魇
Slowly but surely, making our way up to Monstruous Nightmare.
但是谁能够得到杀死龙的荣耀呢?   一定是我 命中注定的
But who'll win the honor of killing it?   It's gonna be me. It's my destiny. See?
你妈妈同意你文身?   这不是文身 这是胎记
Your mom let you get a tattoo?   It's not a tattoo. It's a birth mark.
好吧 我从出生就和你在一起 但是从没有见到过
Okay, I've been stuck with you since birth and that was never there before.
是的 这是胎记 因为你从不看我的左边
Yes, it was. You've just never seen me to the left side until now.
嘿 无牙 我拿早饭来了
Hey, Toothless. I brought breakfast.
我希望  我希望你饥肠辘辘了
I hope... I hope you're hungry.
好吧 这确实很恶心
Okay, that's disgusting.
我拿来了一些鲑鱼 冰岛鳕鱼 还有鳗鱼
I got some salmon, some nice Icelandic cod, and a whole smoked eel.
不 不 不 不  不  好吧
No, no, no, no... no... Okay.
是 我也不喜欢鳗鱼
Yeah, I don't really like eel much either.
就是这样 这可是好东西 别管我
That's it. That's the good stuff. Aah, don't you mind me.
我马上回来 忙我自己的事情
I'll just be back here, minding my own business.
没事的
It's okay...
好的 好的
Okay, okay...
好 这不糟糕 起作用了
Okay, that's not too bad. It works.
不 不 不 不 不 !
No, no, no, no, no, no...!
哦天哪  成功了!
Oh my... It's working!
是的 是的 我做到了
Yes, yes, I did it.
今天的重点是团队合作
Today, is about teamwork.
如果龙头湿了就不能点火了
Now, a wet dragon head can't light its fire.
丑陋Zippleback非常麻烦
The Hideous Zippleback is extra tricky.
一个头放出气体 另一个头点燃
One head breathes gas. The other head lights it.
你们的任务是分清楚头
Your job is to know which is which.
剃刀般锋利的牙齿 对猎物注入毒液帮助消化
Razorsharp serrated teeth, and injects venom for predigestion.
喜欢伏击 压碎敌人
Prefers ambush attack, crushing its victims.
你就不能消停会儿吗?!
Will you please stop that?!
如果龙露出它的任意一张脸 我就要
If that dragon shows either of his faces, I'm gonna...
那里!
There!
嘿 是我 白痴!
Hey, it's us, idiots!
你的屁股越来越大 我们还以为是龙呢
Your butts are getting bigger we thought you were a dragon.
有个龙屁股也没什么不好
Not that there's anything wrong with a dragonass fig...
等等
Wait...
哦! 哦 我受伤了! 我受伤了!
Oh! Oh, I'm hurt! I am very much hurt!
生存的机会越来越渺茫了
Chances of survival are dwindling into single digits now.
哦! 搞错头了
Oh! Wrong head.
Fishlegs啊!
Fishlegs!
快 Hiccup!
Now Hiccup!
哦 来吧
Aww, come on...
Hiccup啊!
Hiccup!
后退 后退 后退!
Back, back, back!
别让我再说一次!
Now don't you make me tell you again!
好 这才是啊 回到笼子里去!
Yes, that's right. Back into your cage!
好好反省你做了什么
Now think about what you've done.
好 嗯嗯 可以了吧?
Okay, sooo, were we done?
我还有事要做 呃  明天见
'Cause I have some things I need to uh... Yep, I'll see you tomorrow.
嘿!
Hey!
那是怎么回事?   你怎么做到的?
What was that?   How did you do that?
我把斧头忘在训练场了 你们先走
I left my axe back in the ring. You guys go on ahead.
我等下赶上来
I'll catch up with you.
见识一下恶龙Terror
Meet the Terrible Terror.
哈! 它的个头只有我的
Ha! It's like the size of my...
哦! 滚开!
Oooh! Get it off!
哦 我受伤了! 疼死我了!
Oh, I'm hurt! I am very much hurt!
哇喔! 他比你厉害多了
Wow! He's better than you ever were.
什么?
What?
哦 好吧
Ooh, great.
Hiccup啊
Hiccup.
Hiccup? 你在吗?
Hiccup? Are you in there?
Astrid 嘿 Astrid 你好 Astrid
Astrid, hey. Hi, Astrid. Hi Astrid. Hi Astrid
我一般不在乎别人在做什么 但你的举止有点诡异
I normally don't care what people do, but you're acting weird.
呃 有点神秘
Well, weirder.
嗯 我相信 你们至少找到了老巢吧?
Well, I trust you found the nest at least?
连影都没见着
Not even close.
很好
Excellent.
我希望 你能把我比下去
I hope you had a little more success than me.
嗯 说到成就 如果你是指没有了家教方面的麻烦
Well, if by success, you mean that your parenting troubles are over with...
那么 是的
then, yes.
祝贺你 Stoick! 大家都感到很宽慰
Congratulations Stoick! Everyone is so relieved.
旧的不去 新的不来 是吧?
Out with the old, and in with the new, right?
没有人会想念那个讨厌鬼
No one will miss that old nuisance.
村子里正开派对在庆祝呢
The village is throwing a party to celebrate.
他出去了?
He's gone?
嗯 是的 多数下午都有出去 但是何必责怪他呢?
Um, yeah, most afternoons, but who can blame him?
我是说 名人的生活也不简单
I mean, the life of a celebrity is very rough.
在村子里 他总是被一群人追捧 让他寸步难行
He can barely walk through the village without being swarmed by his new fans.
Hiccup?   没有人能想到 啊?
Hiccup?   Who would have thought it, eh?
对付那些怪兽 他有一套
He has this way with the beasts.
好了 伙计 我现在得慢慢来
Okay there, bud, were gonna take this nice and slow.
来吧 来吧 三号部位 不 四号部位
Here we go. Here we go. Position three, no, four.
好了 是时候了 好戏上场了
Alright, it's go time. It's go time.
加油 伙计 加油 伙计
Come on, buddy. Come on, buddy.
太好了 成功了!
Yes, it works!
抱歉!
Sorry!
我错了
That's my fault.
嗯 好的 我正在努力 四号部位 呃 是三号
Yeah, yeah, I'm on it. Position four, uh, three.
太好了! 宝贝!
Yeah! Go baby!
噢 太神奇了! 这风在我
Oh, this is amazing! The wind in my...
小抄!
cheat sheet!
不要!
Stop!
不!
No!
噢 糟了! 噢 天哪!
Oh, Gosh! Oh, God!
哦 不!
Oh no!
好了 你得让自己控制方向!
Alright. Okay. You gotta kinda angle yourself!
好了 不 不 不  朝我飞过来
Okay. No, no, no... Come back down towards me.
再近一点  啊!
Come back down... Oww!
太棒了!
Yeah!
不是吧
Come on...
噢 我不用 谢谢了
Uh, no thanks. I'm good.
体内不够耐火啊 是吗?
Not so fireproof on the inside, are you?
来吧
Here you go.
我们完全误解你们了
Everything we know about you guys is wrong.
爸爸 你回来了!
Dad, you're back!
Gobber不在这儿 所以
Gobber's not here, so...
我知道
I know.
我是来找你的
I came looking for you.
是吗?   你一直鬼鬼祟祟的
You did?   You've been keeping secrets.
我有这样吗?
I have?
你觉得你可以藏多久呢?
Just how long did you think you could hide it from me?
我  我不知道你在
I... I don't know what you...
这个岛上发生的一切 我都了如指掌
Nothing happens on this island, without me hearing about it.
噢?
Oh?
所以 让我们来说  说那条龙
So, lets talk... about that dragon
噢 天啊
Oh Gods...
爸爸 我很抱歉 我
Dad, I'm so sorry. I...
我本打算告诉你的 只是我不知道该怎么
I was going to tell you, I just didn't know how to uh...
你  你不担心了?   什么啊? 这正是我期待的!
You... you're not upset?   What? I was hoping for this!
啊 你?   相信我
Ah, you were?   And believe me...
只会越来越好 就等你首次取出一条Nadder的内脏
It only gets better. Just wait till you spill a Nadder's guts for the first time...
用矛取下Gronckle的首级
and mount your first Gronckle head on a spear.
多棒的感觉啊! 这就是我所期待的你 孩子
What feeling! You really had me going there, son.
过去的那么多年里 维京人博克族中最差劲的人
All those years of the worst Viking Berk has ever seen.
主神啊 真不容易啊 我几乎对你不抱期望了
Odin, it was rough. I almost gave up on you.
而你却一直紧随我之后
And all the while you were holding out on me.
噢 万能的托尔神啊!
Oh, Thor almighty!
鉴于你在场上的优秀表现
With you doing so well in the ring...
我们终于有了共同话题
we finally have something to talk about.
我 呃 我给你带来了一个东西
I uh, I brought you something...
让你免受伤害
to keep you safe in the ring.
哇 谢谢
Wow, thanks.
你母亲希望你戴上它
Your mother would wanted you to have it.
这是用她的半个胸甲铸造的
It's half of her breast plate.
我们的是一套 你要知道 让她  更靠近我们
Matching set. Keeps her... Keeps her close, you know.
戴上它吧 会你无比自豪的 这是你应得的
Wear it proudly. You deserve it.
你履行了你的诺言
You've held your end of the deal.
我得上床睡觉了
I should really get to bed.
是的 好的 行 聊得很开心   是的
Yes, good, okay, good talk.   Yeah...
我会去找你的 好了 谢谢你来看我
I'll see you back at the house. Great. Thanks for stopping by and...
呃 还有  胸帽   我希望你会喜欢 呃  这个头盔
the uh... breast hat.   I hope you like the, umm... the hat.
嗯 晚安
Well, good night.
别挡道 胜利是我的!
Stay out of my way. I'm winning this thing!
好的 请吧 当然可以
Good. Please. By all means.
就这次了 一次成功!
This time! This time for sure!
不! 不 妖娘养的 好吃懒做的饭桶 !
No! No, sonofa half troll, rateating munch bucket...!
等等! 等等!
Wait! Wait.
那么  待会见哦
So... later.
噢 噢! 还没呢!   我快迟到了
Oh, oh! Not so fast!   I'm kinda late for...
什么! 到底是迟到什么?
What! Late for what, exactly?
好了 安静下 前辈们已经做好决定了
Okay, quiet down. The Elder has decided.
小家伙 你做到了! 你做到了 Hiccup!
Boy, you've done it! You've done it, Hiccup!
你将杀死那条龙!
You get to kill the dragon!
那才是我的儿子!
That's my boy!
是啊! 是的 我迫不及待了 我太
Yeah! Yes, I can't wait. I am so...
走吧 我们要上路了
leaving. We're Leaving.
我们收拾东西吧
Let's pack up.
貌似你和我要一起度个假
Looks like you and me are taking a little vacation.
没有尽头的假期
Forever.
啊 老兄啊
Awww, man.
什么啊 ? 啊 你  在这干什么呢?
What the...? Uh, w... what are you doing here?
我想知道事情的真相
I want to know what's going on.
没有人可以做的跟你一样好
No one just get as good as you do.
特别是  你
Especially... you.
快说   我  我
Start talking.   I... I...
是不是有人跟你一起训练?
Are you training with someone?
训练? 我没有
Training? I didn't...
最好没有
It better not involve this.
我知道 这看上去很不厚道 但你看 这是
I know, this looks really bad but you see, this is...
你说对了 你说对了 说对了 我  我再也不想扯谎了
You're right. You're right. You're right. I... I'm through with the lies.
我一直在做  装备!
I've been making... outfits!
所以 被你发现了 现在大家也该知道了
So, you got me. It's time everyone knew.
把我拖回去吧 来吧 来啊
Drag me back. Go ahead. Here we go.
啊 你为什么这样?
Oww. Why would you do that?
这是骗子的下场!
That's for the lies!
而这  是关于其他事情的了断!
And that's... for everything else!
噢 老兄
Oh man.
趴下!
Get down!
快跑! 快跑!
Run! Run!
不! 不! 没事 不要紧 她是一个朋友
No! No! It's okay. It's okay. She's a friend.
你刚刚吓到它了
You just scared him.
我吓到它了?
I scared him?
它是谁?
Who is him?
Astrid 这是无牙 无牙 这是Astrid
Astrid, Toothless. Toothless, Astrid.
哒哒哒  我们死定了
Dut, da da... We're dead.
哇啊 哇啊 哇啊 你要去哪里?
Woah, woah woah. Where do you think your going?
噢 主神啊! 不要啊 噢 这
Oh, great Odin! Don't. Oh, this is...
Hiccup 让我下去!
Hiccup, get me down from here!
我必须给我一个解释的机会
You have to give me a chance to explain.
你说什么我都不会听的!
I am not listening to anything you have to say!
那我不说话 让我演示给你看
Then I won't speak. Just let me show you.
拜托了 Astrid
Please, Astrid.
快放我下来!
Now get me down!
无牙 轻轻地飞下去
Toothless, down. Gently.
看见了吧 没什么可怕的
See, nothing to be afraid of.
无牙?
Toothless?
你怎么了? 你这个恶龙!
What is wrong with you? Bad dragon!
它 呃 它一般情况是不会这样的
He's uh, he's not usually like this.
噢 不!
Oh, no!
无牙 你要干什么? 我得讨她喜欢!
Toothless, what are you doing? We need her to like us!
你还打转转!
And now he's spinning!
太感谢你了 你这没用的爬行动物!
Thank you for nothing you useless reptile!
好了 我很抱歉 抱歉 只要把我放下去就好了
Okay, I am sorry, I'm sorry. Just get me off of this thing.
好吧 我承认 这实在是太酷了
Alright, I admit it. This is pretty cool.
太神奇了 它太了不起了
It's amazing. He's amazing.
然后呢?
So what now?
Hiccup 下周就是你的最终考核了!
Hiccup, your final exam is tomorrow!
你知道 你必须得杀死一条
You know your gonna have to kill a...
杀死一条龙
kill a dragon...
不用你提醒
Don't remind me.
无牙 怎么了?
Toothless, what happening?
哇哦 是什么?
Whoa, what is it?
趴下!
Get down!
怎么回事?   我不知道
What's going on?   I don't know.
无牙 你得把我们从这带出去 伙计
Toothless, you gotta get us out of here, bud.
它们貌似在搬运猎物
It looks like they're hauling in their kill.
难不成我们也成猎物了?
What does that make us?
我爸爸是不可能找到这里的
What my dad wouldn't give to find this.
噢 真是令人欣慰 原来我们的粮食都倾倒在这里了
Oh, it's satisfying to know that all of our food has been dumped down a hole.
它们自己没有吃掉
They're not eating any of it.
那是什  什么?
What... was that?
好了 伙计 我们现在必须离开这里了 快!
Alright, bud, we gotta get out of here. Now!
不 不 完全是讲得通的 这就像一个巨大的蜂巢
No, no, it totally makes sense. It's like a giant beehive.
它们就是劳工 而那就是它们的女王
They're the workers, and that's their queen.
它控制着它们 我们现在去找你爸爸
It controls them. Let's find your dad.
不 不
No, no.
不 现在还不行 他们会杀了无牙的
No. Not yet. They'll kill Toothless.
Astrid 我们得仔细想清楚
Astrid, we have to think this through, carefully.
Hiccup 我刚刚发现了一个龙穴
Hiccup, we just discovered the dragon's nest.
这可是我们维京人定居此地以来一直寻求的
The thing we've been after since Vikings first sailed here.
而你却想保守秘密?
And you want to keep it secret?
为了保护你的宠物龙? 你说真的吗?
To protect your pet, dragon? Are you serious?
是的
Yes.
好吧 那我们该怎么做呢?
Okay. Then what do we do?
给我一晚上的时间 我会想出办法的
Just give me until tomorrow. I'll figure something out.
好的
Okay...
这是绑架我的惩罚
That's for kidnapping me.
这是  其他所有事情的报答
That's for... everything else.
你在看什么?
What are you looking at?
嗯 我再次抛头露面了
Well, I can show my face in public again.
如果在几周前 有人告诉我
If someone had told me that in a few short weeks
Hiccup会从一个  呃 成为一个Hiccup
Hiccup will go from... well being... uh... Hiccup,
并在训练中勇争第一
to placing first in dragon training.
嗯 以免他疯言疯语 我会把他绑在桅杆上 然后将他遣送出境
Well, I would have tied him to a mast and shipped him off. For fear he'd gone mad.
而你们也知道
And you know it.
但是 现在
But, here we are.
没人能比我更惊讶或者更自豪
And no ones more surprised or more proud than I am.
今天 我的儿子成为了一名真正的维京勇士!
Today my boy becomes a Viking!
今天他成为了我们中的一员!
Today he becomes one of us!
当心那条龙
Be careful with that dragon.
并不是龙让我担忧
It's not the dragon I'm worried about.
你打算怎么办?
What are you going to do?
平息这一切
Put an end to this.
我得试一试
I have to try.
Astrid 如果我遭逢不测 千万别让他们找到无牙
Astrid, if something goes wrong, just make sure they don't find Toothless.
我会的 你得向我保证你会平平安安的
I will, just promise me it won't go wrong.
时间到了 Hiccup
It's time, Hiccup.
放倒它们
Knock 'em dead.
我会选铁锤
I'd have gone for the hammer.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
加油 Hiccup 给它点颜色看看!
Go on Hiccup, give it to him!
他在干什么?
What is he doing?
没关系 没事的
It's okay, it's okay.
我并非他们那类人
I'm not one of them.
他在想什么?
What's he thinking?
停止打斗!
Stop the fight!
不! 我需要大家来见证
No! I need you all to see this.
它们并非我们想的那样
They're not what we think they are.
我们不必杀死它们
We don't have to kill them.
我说了 停止打斗!
I said stop the fight!
让开 别挡道!
Out of my way!
Hiccup啊!
Hiccup!
这边!
This way!
夜煞!
Night Fury!
好了 无牙 快走! 离开这
Alright, Toothless. Go! Get out of here.
走 快走!
Go, go!
不 爸爸! 爸爸 它不会伤害你们的!
No, dad! Dad, he won't hurt you!
无牙 停下!
Toothless, stop!
不 不!
No. No!
捉住它!
Get him!
不不 求求你们 别伤害它
No, no, please. Just don't hurt him
拜托 别伤害它
Please. Don't hurt him
和其他的关到一起
Put it with the others.
我早该明白
I should have known.
我早该注意到这些迹象
I should have seen the signs.
爸爸?   我们达成了协议!
Dad?   We had a deal!
我知道! 我们说好了 但是那是在我  哦 全都被搞得一团糟
I know! We did, but that was before I... Oh, it's all so messed up.
那么斗兽场上的一切  是一场骗局? 一个谎言?
So everything in that ring... A trick? A lie?
我搞砸了 之前我就该告诉你
I screwed up. I should have told you before now.
都是我的错 冲我发火吧 但是求求你 就是不要伤害无牙
Take this out on me, be mad at me, but please, just don't hurt Toothless.
那条龙? 那就是你担心的?
The dragon? That's what you're worried about?
而不是几乎被你杀害的人?
Not the people you almost killed?
它只是在保护我! 它并不危险
He was just protecting me! He's not dangerous.
它们已经杀了我们几百号人!
They've killed hundreds of us!
我们也杀了它们数以千计的同类 它们是自卫 仅此而已
And we've killed thousands of them. They defend themselves, that's all.
它们袭击我们也是万不得已
They raid us because they have to.
如果它们没带回足够的食物 自己就会被吃掉
If they don't bring enough food back, they'll be eaten themselves.
它们的岛上还有别的生物 是一种像龙的
There's something else on their island, dad. It's a dragonlike...
它们的岛? 所以说 你去过它们的巢穴?
Their island? So, you've been to the nest?
我说了巢穴吗?   你怎么找到的?
Did I say nest?   How did you find it?
不不 不是我 是无牙找到的 只有龙才找得到那个岛
No, no, I didn't. Toothless did. Only a dragon can find the island.
不不 爸 不要 求求你 那里不是你想的那样
No, no, dad, no please. It's not what you think.
你不知道你会面临什么 那是你前所未见的
You don't know what your up against. It's like nothing you've ever seen.
爸爸 求求你 我向你保证 你不可能获胜!
Dad, please, I promise you. You can't win this one!
爸爸 不!
Dad, no!
这辈子 你就不能听我一次吗!
For once in your life, would you please just listen to me!
你已经成为它们中的一份子
You've thrown your lot in with them.
你不是一名维京勇士
You're not a Viking.
你不是我儿子!
You're not my son!
备船!
Ready the ships!
启航!
Set sail!
向地狱犬之门前进
We head for Hell Hounds gate.
带我们归巢吧 恶魔
Lead us home, devil.
真是一团糟 你肯定感到恐惧
It's a mess. You must feel horrible.
你已经失去了一切 你的父亲 族人和最好的朋友
You've lost everything. Your father, your tribe, your best friend.
谢谢你的总结
Thank you for summing that up.
为什么当我在树林里发现那条龙时 没有杀了它呢?
Why couldn't I've killed that dragon, when I found him the woods?
那样可能对大伙更好
Would've been better for everyone.
嗯 其他人可能会这么做
Yep, the rest of us would have done it.
那么 为什么你不这样做?
So, why didn't you?
为什么不这样做?
Why didn't you?
我不知道 我做不到
I don't know. I couldn't.
这不算回答   为什么突然间 这对你这么重要?
That's not an answer.   Why is this so important to you all of a sudden?
因为我想记住你说的话 快说
Because I want to remember what you say, right now.
啊 因为是爱  我是个懦夫 我很软弱
Ah, for the love of... I was coward, I was weak.
我不愿去杀龙!
I wouldn't kill a dragon!
你刚刚说 你不愿意杀龙?
You said wouldn't that time?
无论如何 我不愿意!
Whatever, I wouldn't!
300年了 我是第一个不愿杀龙的维京人
300 years and I'm the first Viking who wouldn't kill a dragon.
却是第一个骑龙的
First to ride one though.
所以?
So?
我不愿杀它 因为它看起来和我一样受到了惊吓
I wouldn't kill him because he looked as frightened as I was.
我看见它 就像看到了自己
I looked at him and I saw myself.
我确信它现在很恐惧
I bet he's really frightened now.
那你打算怎么办?
What are you gonna do about it?
可能会做些蠢事
Probably something stupid.
很好 但是你已经做了
Good, but you've already done that.
那么做些疯狂的事吧!
Then something crazy!
这才像话
That's more like it.
测量船距! 保持在听力范围之内
Sound your positions! Stay within earshot.
听着 Stoick 我刚刚偷听到有人 嗯 你明白
Listen, Stoick, I was overhearing some of the men just now and well, you know...
有人好奇 我们这次来这的目的是什么?
some of them are wondering what it is we're up to here?
当然不是我 你知道你一向是个有计划的人
Not me of course. I know you are always the man with the plan.
但是有些人 不是我 想知道实际上是否有个计划
But some, not me, are wondering if there is in fact a plan at all...
还有 计划大致是什么?
and what it might be?
找到它们的巢穴 并摧毁它
Find the nest and take it.
当然 让它们四处逃窜 老一辈维京勇士没有取胜 应该是小菜一碟吧
Of course. Send them running. The old Viking fallback. Nice and simple.
让开
Step aside.
向左转舵
Head to port.
如果你打算被吃掉 我更愿意去陪着Gronckle
If you're planning on getting eaten, I'd definitely go with the Gronckle.
如果你明智地选择 从世界上最致命的武器那寻求帮助
You were wise to seek help from the world's most deadly weapon.
那就是我
It's me.
我爱这个计划!   我不
I love this plan!   I didn't...
你太疯狂了 我喜欢
You're crazy. I like that.
那么 有什么计划?
So, what is the plan?
形势不妙啊
That's not very encouraging.
哦 我很好奇它要去哪
Oh, I was wondering where that went.
保持警惕 准备武器
Stay low, and ready your weapons.
我们到了
We're here.
等等 你要干  ?!
Wait, what are you... ?!
没问题  没问题
It's okay... It's okay.
你去哪?
Where are you going?
你还需要点东西 帮助你继续下去
You're gonna need something to help you hold on.
当我们砸开这座山时 所有畜生都会倾巢而出
When we crack this mountain open, all hell is gonna break loose.
那会吓得尿裤子 好在我多带了几条
In my undies. Good thing I brought extras.
无论结局如何 一切将在今天结束
No matter how this ends, it ends today.
就这样?
Is that it?
我们成功了!
We've done it!
还没完!
This isn't over!
整队 团结一致!
Form your ranks. Pull together!
撤退!
Get clear!
这是雷神托尔的胡须吗 ! 那是什么?
Beards of Thor...! What is that?
主神奥汀(托尔之父) 救救我们吧!
Odin, help us!
弹弩!   发射!
Catapults!   Fire!
上船!   不 不!
Get to the ships!   No, nooo!
不是那艘    我傻了
Not that one...   I was a fool.
带大伙去岛屿的另一侧
Lead the men to the far side of the island.
Gobber 和大家一起走
Gobber, go with the men.
我想我决定留下来 以防你想做什么疯狂的事
I think I'll stay, just in case you're thinking of doing something crazy.
如果我让那东西有目标可寻 那么还能争取到一些时间
I can buy them a few minutes if I give that thing something to hunt for.
那我可以让时间翻倍
Then I can double that time.
到这来!   哦 不 到这来!
Here!   Oh, no. Here!
来打我啊!   不 打我!
Fight me!   No, me!
Ruff Tuff 小心你们的后面!
Ruff, Tuff, watch your backs!
前进 Fishlegs!
Move, Fishlegs!
看我们! 我们骑着龙! 我们骑着龙! 我们所有人!
Look at us! We're on dragons! We're on dragons! All of us!
每个维京勇士都是固执顽强的 就像你一样
Every bit the bullheaded stubborn Viking you ever were.
Fishlegs 说明详情!   好的
Fishlegs, break it down!   Okay.
颅骨和尾部覆有厚重铠甲 有助于猛击和压碎物体 要闪避这两处
Heavily armored skull and tail made for bashing and crushing. Steer clear of both.
小眼睛和大鼻孔 它主要依靠听觉和嗅觉
Small eyes, large nostrils. Relies on hearing and smell.
好的 Lout Legs 飞至它的盲区 制造噪音给它混淆试听
Okay, Lout, Legs, hang in its blind spot. Make some noise. Keep it confused.
Ruff Tuff 查明它是否有射击次数限制 并激怒它
Ruff, Tuff, find out if it has a shot limit. Make it mad.
这是我的拿手好戏!   什么时候开始?
That's my specialty!   Since when?
大家都知道 我最让人恼火 看
Everyone knows I'm more irritating, see.
就照我说的去做 我会尽快回来
Just do what I told you. I'll be back as soon as I can.
别担心 我们为你做掩护!
Don't worry! We got it covered!
好!
Yeah!
傻子!   蠢货!
Fool!   Butto!
再见 白痴!
Bye, ya Grendel!
呃 这东西没有盲区!
Um, this thing doesn't have a blind spot!
那里!
There!
去帮其他人!
Go help the others!
好的 等等 等等
Okay, hold on. Hold on.
起作用了!   嗯 奏效了!
It's working!   Yeah, it's working!
我已经没法控制Gronckle了! Snotlout 看你的了!
I've lost power on the Gronckle! Snotlout, do something!
我没事!
I'm okay!
勉强没事
Less okay.
我不能错失良机! 怎么样 伙计? 觉得眼睛里有东西?
I can't miss! What's wrong, buddy? You got something in your eye?
是的 你是维京勇士!
Yeah, you're the Viking!
呜啊!
Woah!
爸爸?
Dad?
你成功了 伙计!
You got it, buddy!
Hiccup啊!
Hiccup!
对不起
I'm sorry...
我为  为所有事道歉
for... for everything.
嗯  我也是
Yeah... me too.
你不必到那去
You don't have to go up there.
我们是维京勇士 这是渗入进骨子里的冒险精神
We're Vikings. It's an occupational hazard...
你是我儿子 我为你骄傲
I'm proud to call you my son.
谢谢 爸爸
Thanks, Dad.
他来了!
He's up!
带Snotlout离开!
Get Snotlout outta there!
我骑着它!   我先骑的!
I'm on it!   I'm on it first!
嘿 让我骑!
Hey, let me drive!
别推我!   我拔光你的牙!
Don't push me!   I'll push your teeth out!
你知道吗 我无法相信这成功了
You know, I can't believe that worked.
夜煞!   趴下!
Night Fury!   Get down!
你抓住她了吗?
Did you get her?
走!
Go!
这家伙有翅膀 好吧 让我们看看它会不会用!
This thing has wings. Okay, let's see if it can use them!
你觉得它飞过吗?
You think that did it?
嗯 它会飞
Well, he can fly.
好吧 无牙 没时间了! 来吧 伙计!
Okay, Toothless, time to disappear! Come on, bud!
它来了!
Here it comes!
当心!
Watch out!
好吧 时间到 看看这样是否有效
Okay, time's up. Let's see if this works.
来吧! 这就是你全部的本事吗?
Come on! Is that the best you can do?
陪着我 伙计 我们没问题 只要再坚持一会儿
Stay with me, buddy. We're good. Just a little bit longer.
坚持住 无牙 小心!
Hold, Toothless. Now!
不  不!
No... No!
Hiccup! Hiccup啊!
Hiccup! Hiccup!
儿子!
Son!
Hiccup啊!
Hiccup!
哦 儿子!
Oh son!
我一手造成的
I did this.
对  对不起
I'm s... I'm so sorry.
Hiccup啊!
Hiccup!
他还活着! 你让他重生!
He's alive! You brought him back alive!
谢谢你  救了我的儿子
Thank you... for saving my son.
呃 你知道 救了他的大部分
Well, you know, most of him.
嘿 无牙
Hey, Toothless.
我也很高兴见到你 伙计
Happy to see you too, buddy.
啊 什么  呃  我  在家
Aawww, what... uh... I'm... in my house
你在我家
You're in my house.
我爸爸知道你在这吗?
Does my dad know you're here?
嗯 什么 哦 好吧  好吧
Uh, what, oh, okay... okay.
无牙 不 无牙! 啊 别这样
Toothless, no. Toothless! Aw, come on.
好吧 谢谢 伙计
Okay. Thanks, bud.
无牙 留在这
Toothless, stay here.
大家来吧 准备好! 抓紧 我们走!
C'mon guys. Get ready! Hold on tight. Here we go!
什么?
What?
我懂了 我死了
I knew it. I'm dead.
不 但是你给了它最棒的一击
No, but you give it your best shot.
那么 你觉得怎么样?
So, what do you think?
嘿 看 是Hiccup!
Hey look, it's Hiccup!
Hiccup啊!
Hiccup!
事实证明 我们更需要的是  这样的你
It turns out, all we needed was a little more of... this.
你刚指的是我的全部?
You just gestured to all of me?
嗯 你的大部分 那小部分是我的作品
Well, most of you. That bit's my handiwork.
加入了一点Hiccup的光芒 你觉得怎么样?
With a little Hiccup flare thrown in. You think that'll do?
我可能需要做几次微调
I might make a few tweaks.
这一下  是因为你吓到我了
That's... for scaring me.
什么  什么 总要这样吗? 因为
What... what, is it always going to be this way? Because...
我会习惯的
I could get used to it.
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
夜煞!   趴下!
Night Fury!   Get down!
你准备好了吗?
You ready?
这里是博克岛
This is Berk...
一年下九个月的雪 另三个月下冰雹
It snows nine months of the year and hails the other three.
任何生长在这的食物都坚硬无味
Any food that grows here is tough and tasteless.
生长在这的人们更是坚韧不拔
The people that grow here are even more so.
唯一的好处就是宠物
The only upsides are the pets.
当别的地方饲养小马或者鹦鹉时
While other places have ponies or parrots...
我们却拥有
We have...
龙
Dragons.